# Manik Chaudhary

### Lead Software Test Automation Engineer

9+ Years of experience in application analysis, design, development and Automation. Skilled Automation Tester with demonstrated success as a team leader and resource manager. Ready to leverage experience in new role with potential for long-term growth and advancement. Focused on training team members and completing full program reviews at all stages of development.



manik1441@gmail.com

09643505814



Hyderabad

in linkedin.com/in/manik-chaudhary-91902b59

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Lead Software Test Automation Engineer** Google - EPAM Systems

04/2022 - Present

Hyderabad, TN, India

GO3-ENGC - Governance, risk and compliance (GRC)

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Customer collboration and negotiation
- Analysing the Requirements from the PO
- Implementation of new modules in existing Automation framework using Python
- Performing Code review
- Monitor team performance and report on metrics
- Mentoring new joiners and participate in evaluation of the candidates for the project
- Delegate tasks and set deadlines
- Playing role of Resource Manager as well.

# Senior Software Test Automation Engineer

Medicision - EPAM System

Hyderabad, TN, India

Our software engineering heritage combined with our strategic business and innovation consulting, design thinking, and physical-digital capabilities provide real business value to our customers through human-centric innovation.

#### Achievements/Tasks

08/2021 - 04/2022

- Creation of new modules in the existing Automation framework based on Python with BDD and pytest for UI testing (Selenium) and API testing.
- Ownership of the regression suite and scheduling the jobs via CI/CD pipelines.
- Code and Script review before pushing to Dev and Integration branch.
- Played role of Scrum Master

# Software Developer Engineer in Test II **S&P GLOBAL PVT LTD**

07/2019 - 08/2021

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

S&P Global promotes sustainable growth in the global capital, commodity and corporate markets by providing customers with essential intelligence.

- Creation of new modules in the existing Automation framework(CAFe) as per the requirement and Optimization of the existing scripts based on C#,Python and Java(Selenium WebDriver).
- Creation of **BDD** s as per the requirement.
- Ownership of the regression suite job in release.
- Peer reviewing code developed by my colleagues.
- Provided POC of performance testing using Locust in house tool(CAFe).
- Gather, analyse and Perforom Database testing using hive.

### SKILLS

**TOSCA** Robot Framework UI/API Testing REST/SOAP SAFe 5.0 Load Runner/Jmeter JSON **Automation Testing Functional Testing** Performance Testing Oracle/SQL People Management

# CERTIFICATIONS

Tricentis Tosca Fundamentals (09/2023) Affiliated by Tricentis

Professional Scrum Master (01/2022) Affiliated by Scrum Org

PCEP - Python Entry Level Programmer (05/2021)

Affiliated by Python Institute

SAFe 5.0 Practioner (02/2021)

Affiliated by Scaled Agile, Inc.

ISTOB Certified Tester Foundation Level (02/2020)

Affiliated by GASQ

# **LANGUAGE**

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineer

#### Guardian India Solutions PVT LTD

#### 03/2018 - 07/2019

Gurgaon, India

It is involved in Software publishing, consultancy and supply (Software publishing includes production, supply and documentation of Legacy software.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Collecting and analyzing requirements from business and providing POC to the team.
- Development of the Code on back-end and front end modules.
- Trouble-shooting and fixing bugs.
- Creation of Automation Script on Selenium WebDriver for regression testing.

# **Quality Assurance Engineer**Softtech India PVT LTD

#### 10/2014 - 03/2018

Guraaon.India

It is part of the Soft Tech Group, an international software solution provider for Fenestration industry with global footprints in USA, UK, France, Australia, India and New Zealand.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Analyzing the Requirements from the client
- Logging defects using TFS and Freshdesk, involve in resolving defects with developers
- Performed Sanity Testing and Smoke Testing
- Developed Test scenarios, Test Scripts and Test cases based on Requirements
- Preparing Defect Report and giving mandatory information of a defect to developers in order to fix it
- Followed Agile (scrum) methodology throughout the project.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Technology**

Galgotias college of Engineering and Technology

07/2013

Greater Noida, UP, India

# PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

#### Google - GGRC

- The GGRC project has the goal to provide a solution to manage the challenges that come with complying with regulations. It provides a system to record information and capture the relationships between all the pieces.
- Team OA Team: 14.
- Tools/Technologies Selenium, Python, Pytest, GIT, Intellij, Notepad++, Gerrit, pylint, Google workspace, Gcloud, API Testing, POM, Agile, kokoro.

#### Medecision

- Medecision is a digital care management company whose solutions and services are used by leading health plans and care delivery organizations to support more than 42 million people nationwide.
- Team QA Team: 8
- Tools Postman, Pycharm, Notepad++, Dbeaver, Oracle sql Developer, Beyond Comapre
- Technologies Python, API Testing, Functional Testing, Agile

#### **S&P CAPITAL IO**

- Capital IQ is the research division of Standard and Poor's. It provides detailed research and analysis of the stock market to a variety of investing stakeholders.
- Team Dev Team: 8, QA Team: 3.
- Tools Selenium Webdriver, Postman, Swagger, GIT, TFS, Pycharm, Intellij, Notepad++, Dbeaver, Oracle sql Developer, Beyond Comapre, Gherkin, Visual Studio Professional 2019, Zeppellin Database - Oracle, Cassandra.
- Technologies Java, Python, C#, API Testing, BDD, Agile.

#### Amazon PLOA

- PLOA is the module under Leave Absence Management System named AM360 which automate the approval/denial of the leaves as per the situations.
- Team Dev Team 8 QA Team- 3.
- Tools JIRA, Eclipse, Sonar, Jenkins, SQL server management Studio, Oracle sql server, SahiPro, SVN, WinSCP, Putty, AutoIT, Notepad++ Database - Oracle.
- Technologies Java, SQL, Regression Testing, HTML